<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" type="text/xml" href="style.xsl"?>
<book>
	<title>
		Everything That Remains
	</title>
	<authors>
		The Minimalists
	</authors>
	<source>
		Library paper book
	</source>
	<highlights>
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>1</highlightID>
			<text>
				... but their careers have changed them, altered them physically and emotionally, ...
			</text>
			<location>16</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>2</highlightID>
			<text>
				Someone once told me that our bodies' cells regenerate every seven years, making as completely new people at seven-year intervals.
			</text>
			<location>16</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>3</highlightID>
			<text>
				Maybe this is my fourth regeneration, my chance at a new start, an opportunity to be kinder to what I've been given, for that's all there is, and the meter is running,
			</text>
			<location>16</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>4</highlightID>
			<text>
				number of things you own
			</text>
			<location>16</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>5</highlightID>
			<text>
				owning very little
			</text>
			<location>16</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>6</highlightID>
			<text>
				act of ownership stressed me
			</text>
			<location>16</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>7</highlightID>
			<text>
				Ask what are you passionate about? Not, what do you.
			</text>
			<location>16</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>8</highlightID>
			<text>
				But then again, most things in life aren't innate.
			</text>
			<location>61</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>9</highlightID>
			<text>
				Progress requires practice and dedication to a certain extent, a healthy obsession. Hence, passion is mixture of love and obsession.
			</text>
			<location>61</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>10</highlightID>
			<text>
				 An issue people rarely talk about these days is what true passion actually feels like. Instead we assume that passion feels like excitement - that passion is inherently exciting - but the assumption is wrong.
			</text>
			<location>63</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>11</highlightID>
			<text>
				Excitement comes and goes; it wanes when times get hard, when the work gets tough, when creative flow turns into drudgery. True passion, however arise after you've put in the long hours necessary to become a skilled craftsman, a skillset you can then leverage to have an impact, to gain autonomy and respect, to shape and control your destiny.
			</text>
			<location>63</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>12</highlightID>
			<text>
				For any dimension of life, for any skill set - be it exercise, ballroom dancing, or writing - a person must be willing to drudge through the drudgery to find joy on the other side.
			</text>
			<location>64</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>13</highlightID>
			<text>
				I've aspired all over the place, writing haphazardly whenenver I get excited - and I excite easily.
			</text>
			<location>64</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>14</highlightID>
			<text>
				The reality of my daily grind is that life's mundane tasks eat up most of my time....
				These activities are my true priorities.
			</text>
			<location>65</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>15</highlightID>
			<text>
				Until I actually put these pursuits first, until I make these undertakings part of my everyday routine, they are not my actual priorities.
			</text>
			<location>65</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>15</highlightID>
			<text>
				What if you removed one material posession - just one - from your life each day for a month? What would happen?
			</text>
			<location>68</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>16</highlightID>
			<text>
				Why declutter? Why do you want to get rid of things?
			</text>
			<location>70</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>17</highlightID>
			<text>
				Do I love this? Does this have a function?
			</text>
			<location></location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>18</highlightID>
			<text>
				Now anytime I feel the urge to hold on to something,, I get rid of it as soon as I hear myself think those words: "just in case"
			</text>
			<location>88</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>19</highlightID>
			<text>
				Careers are dangerous because people invest so much of themselves into their careers that they establish an identity and social status based upon where they work and what they do for a living.
			</text>
			<location>103</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>20</highlightID>
			<text>
				Sure, I need money to pay for the basics, but I don't need to struggle to earn money to buy crap I don't need anymore.
			</text>
			<location>105</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>21</highlightID>
			<text>
				Now, before I spend money, I ask myself one question: Is this worth my freedom?
			</text>
			<location>105</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>22</highlightID>
			<text>
				Basically I no longer waste money, and so it is far less important to pursue it endlessly.
			</text>
			<location>105</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>23</highlightID>
			<text>
				We always asked "What if?" with so much optimism (as kids), but now the only time we seem to ask it is out of fear.
			</text>
			<location>107</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>24</highlightID>
			<text>
				I sit in my chair for 2 hours a day, every day, without any distractions
			</text>
			<location>107</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>25</highlightID>
			<text>
				... exhausted, worn out, but it's that good kind of worn out, how you feel when your mind and body've synchronized, heart and thoughts pulsing at the same rate, on the same continuum, transcending intention...
			</text>
			<location>128</location>
			<note>exercise</note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>26</highlightID>
			<text>
				The point, however, is not to limit myself. My journey toward a simpler life has never been about deprivation. Rather, I limit myself in the short term so I can learn more about me, learn about my psyche, and ultimately identify what is meaningful in my life.
			</text>
			<location>133</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>27</highlightID>
			<text>
				Transference - leveraging one's current skillsets and transferring those skills to new endeavors.
			</text>
			<location>134</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>28</highlightID>
			<text>
				Creativity. If we are constantly consuming we are not creating.
			</text>
			<location>138</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>29</highlightID>
			<text>
				It turns out that killing the Internet at home was the best decision I've ever made with respect to productivity.
			</text>
			<location>141</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>30</highlightID>
			<text>
				If I see something I want to do research on the Web, I just can't jump at the impulse; I have to write it down and use that list during connectivity.
			</text>
			<location>141</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>31</highlightID>
			<text>
				there were three things that significantly changed his life: establishing habits he enjoyed, simplifying his life, and living with no goals
			</text>
			<location>145</location>
			<note>q. Why do I have these goals?
				  a. To give me accountability to myself till it becomes an ingrained habit.
			      q. Decide to live with no goals for a while
			      research: goal-less
			      what is a goal?
			      How to change, resist temptation, be accountable without goals?
			 </note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>32</highlightID>
			<text>
				That is to say, I don't do things I dislike, but I do do a lot of things that force me to feel discomfort.
			</text>
			<location>149</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>33</highlightID>
			<text>
				I don't do much.
			</text>
			<location>150</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>34</highlightID>
			<text>
				The truth is; you can skip the pursuit of happiness altogether and just be happy.
			</text>
			<location>156</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>35</highlightID>
			<text>
				Basically, I take 20 minutes each day to sit quietly, doing nothing with my body. Nothing. No playing computer chess or texting or doodling or reading or watching TV. I just sit or lie awake, alone, smothered in my own thoughts, undisturbed - no phone, no computer, no music - and I just stare off into space, unfocus my eyes, and let my mind wander.
			</text>
			<location>190,191</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>36</highlightID>
			<text>
				It doesn't matter what you think about, just that you know you've got some time to think.
			</text>
			<location>195</location>
			<note>winners</note>
		</highlight>
		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>37</highlightID>
			<text>
				Another way (to start learning)is to start anew. Not unlike kindergarten, this manner of learning ir simultaneously terrifying and exciting, because everything in the atmosphere is so new, so vivid, so uncertain and uncharted. Growth happens rapidly amid the terror and excitement of elementary school.
			</text>
			<location>195</location>
			<note></note>
		</highlight>

		<highlight isNoteOnly="false">
			<highlightID>32</highlightID>
			<reference>Tomorrow and Tomorrow and Tomorrow</reference>	
			<referenceauthors>Aldous Huxley</referenceauthors>
			<toRead>1</toRead>
			<location>153</location>
			<note>Book to read, Essay "The  Education of an amphibian"</note>
		</highlight>

	</highlights>
</book>
