<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" type="text/xml" href="style.xsl"?>
<book>
  <title>
    Nonviolent Communication: A Language of Life
  </title>
  <authors>
    Marshall B. Rosenberg
  </authors>
  <source>
    Library paper book
  </source>

  <highlights>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>1</highlightID>
      <text>
        Words Are Windows 
        (or They're Walls) 
         
        I feel so sentenced by your words, 
        I feel so judged and sent away, 
        Before I go I've got to know, 
        Is that what you mean to say? 
         
        Before I rise to my defense, 
        Before I speak in hurt or fear, 
        Before I build that wall of words, 
        Tell me, did I really hear? 
         
        Words are windows, or they're walls, 
        They sentence us, or set us free. 

        When I speak and when I hear, 
        Let the love light shine through me. 
         
        There are things I need to say, 
        Things that mean so much to me, 
        If my words don't make me clear, 
        Will you help me to be free? 
         
        If I seemed to put you down, 
        If you felt I didn't care, 
        Try to listen through my words, 
        To the feelings that we share. 
         
        –Ruth Bebermeyer
      </text>
      <location>xvii</location>
      <note>eq, poem by Ruth bebermeyer</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>2</highlightID>
      <text>
        NVC guides us in reframing how we express ourselves and hear others. Instead of habitual, automatic reactions, our words become conscious responses based firmly on awareness of what we are perceiving, feeling, and wanting. We are led to express ourselves with honesty and clarity, while simultaneously paying others a respectful and empathic attention.
      </text>
      <location>3</location>
      <note>Why NVC</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>3</highlightID>
      <text>
        As NVC replaces our old patterns of defending, withdrawing, or attacking in the face of judgment and criticism, we come to perceive ourselves and others, as well as our intentions and relationships, in a new light. Resistance, defensiveness, and violent reactions are minimized.
      </text>
      <location>3</location>
      <note>why nvc</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>4</highlightID>
      <text>
        First, we observe what is actually happening in a situation: what are we observing others saying or doing that is either enriching or not enriching our life? The trick is to be able to articulate this observation without introducing any judgment or evaluation - to simply say what people are doing that we either like or don't like. Next, we state how we feel when we observe this action: are we hurt, scared, joyful, amused, irritated? And thirdly, we say what needs of ours are connected to the feelings we have identified.
      </text>
      <location>6</location>
      <note>NVC Process</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>5</highlightID>
      <text>
        NVC Process 
        The concrete actions we 
        observe that affect our well-being

        How we feel in relation 
        to what we observe 
        
        The needs, values, desires, etc. 
        that create our feelings 
        
        The concrete actions we request 
        in order to enrich our lives 
      </text>
      <location>7</location>
      <note>NVC Process</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>6</highlightID>
      <text>
        ""Out beyond ideas of wrongdoing and right-doing, there is a field. I'll meet you there."
      </text>
      <location>15</location>
      <note>eq, Quote by Rumi</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>7</highlightID>
      <text>
        It is important here not to confuse value judgments and moralistic judgments. All of us make value judgments as to the qualities we value in life; for example, we might value honesty, freedom, or peace. Value judgments reflect our beliefs of how life can best be served. We make moralistic judgments of people and behaviors that fail to support our value judgments;
      </text>
      <location>17</location>
      <note>how we judges</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>8</highlightID>
      <text>
        Communication is life-alienating when it clouds our awareness that we are each responsible for our own thoughts, feelings, and actions.
      </text>
      <location>19</location>
      <note>communication, denial of responsibility</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>9</highlightID>
      <text>
        We are dangerous when we are not conscious of our responsibility for how we behave, think, and feel.
      </text>
      <location>21</location>
      <note>denial of responsibility, lack of mindfulness</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>10</highlightID>
      <text>
        Communicating our desires as demands is yet another form of language that blocks compassion. A demand explicitly or implicitly threatens listeners with blame or punishment if they fail to comply.
      </text>
      <location>22</location>
      <note>communication, demands, punishment</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>11</highlightID>
      <text>
        NVC does not mandate that we remain completely objective and refrain from evaluating. It only requires that we maintain a separation between our observations and our evaluations. NVC is a process language that discourages static generalizations; instead, evaluations are to be based on observations specific to time and context.

        When we combine observation with evaluation, people are apt to hear criticism.
      </text>
      <location>26</location>
      <note>observing without evaluating, criticism</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>13</highlightID>
      <text>
        The Indian philosopher J. Krishnamurti once remarked that observing without evaluating is the highest form of human intelligence.
      </text>
      <location>28</location>
      <note>eq, observing without evaluating</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>14</highlightID>
      <text>
        Distinguishing Observations From Evaluations

        The following table distinguishes observations that are separate from evaluation from those that have evaluation mixed in.
        <tr>
          <th>Communication</th>
          <th>Example of observation with evaluation mixed in</th>
          <th>Example of observation separate from evaluation</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>1. Use of verb to be without indication that the evaluator takes responsibility for the evaluation</td>
          <td>You are too generous.</td>
          <td>When I see you give all your lunch money to others, I think you are being too generous.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>2. Use of verbs with evaluative connotations</td>
          <td>Doug procrastinates. </td>
          <td>Doug only studies for exams the night before.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>3. Implication that one's inferences about another person's thoughts, feelings, intentions, or desires are the only ones possible</td>
          <td>She won't get her work in.</td>
          <td>I don't think she'll get her work in. or She said, "I won't get my work in."</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>4. Confusion of prediction with certainty</td>
          <td>If you don't eat balanced meals, your health will be impaired.</td>
          <td>If you don't eat balanced meals, I fear your health may be impaired.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>5. Failure to be specific about referents</td>
          <td>Immigrants don't take care of their property.</td>
          <td>I have not seen the immigrant family living at 1679 Ross shovel the snow on their sidewalk.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>6. Use of words denoting ability without indicating that an evaluation is being made</td>
          <td>Hank Smith is a poor soccer player.</td>
          <td>Hank Smith has not scored a goal in twenty games.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>7. Use of adverbs and adjectives in ways that do not indicate a evaluation has been made</td>
          <td>Jim is ugly.</td>
          <td>Jim's looks don't appeal to me.</td>
        </tr>
      </text>
      <location>30,31</location>
      <note>observing without evaluating</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>15</highlightID>
      <text>
        Distinguish feelings from thoughts.
        Distinguish between what we feel and what we think we are.
      </text>
      <location>41</location>
      <note>feelings vs. thoughts</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>16</highlightID>
      <text>
        Distinguish between what we feel and how we think others react or behave toward us.
      </text>
      <location>42</location>
      <note>feelings vs. thoughts</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>17</highlightID>
      <text>
        Connect your feeling with your need: "I feel ... because I need ...

        we can deepen our awareness of our own responsibility by substituting the phrase, "I feel ... because I ... "
        For example:
        1."I feel really infuriated when spelling mistakes like that appear in our public brochures, because I want our company to project a professional image.
      </text>
      <location>52</location>
      <note>connecting feeling with need</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>18</highlightID>
      <text>
        Stage 1: In this stage, which I refer to as emotional slavery, we believe ourselves responsible for the feelings of others. We think we must constantly strive to keep everyone happy. If they don't appear happy, we feel responsible and compelled to do something about it.
      </text>
      <location>57</location>
      <note>emotional slavery to emotional liberation</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>19</highlightID>
      <text>
        Stage 2: In this stage, we become aware of the high costs of assuming responsibility for others' feelings and trying to accommodate them at our own expense. When we notice how much of our lives we've missed and how little we have responded to the call of our own soul, we may get angry. I refer jokingly to this stage as the obnoxious stage because we tend toward obnoxious comments like, "That's your problem! I'm not responsible for your feelings!" when presented with another person's pain. We are clear what we are not responsible for, but have yet to learn how to be responsible to others in a way that is not emotionally enslaving.
      </text>
      <location>58,59</location>
      <note>emotional slavery to emotional liberation</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>20</highlightID>
      <text>
        Stage 3: At the third stage, emotional liberation, we respond to the needs of others out of compassion, never out of fear, guilt, or shame. Our actions are therefore fulfilling to us, as well as to those who receive our efforts. We accept full responsibility for our own intentions and actions, but not for the feelings of others. At this stage, we are aware that we can never meet our own needs at the expense of others. Emotional liberation involves stating clearly what we need in a way that communicates we are equally concerned that the needs of others be fulfilled.
      </text>
      <location>60</location>
      <note>emotional slavery to emotional liberation</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>21</highlightID>
      <text>
        In the course of developing emotional responsibility, most of us experience three stages: (1) "emotional slavery" - believing ourselves responsible for the feelings of others, (2) "the obnoxious stage" - in which we refuse to admit to caring what anyone else feels or needs, and (3) "emotional liberation"-in which we accept full responsibility for our own feelings but not the feelings of others, while being aware that we can never meet our own needs at the expense of others.
      </text>
      <location>61</location>
      <note>emotional slavery to emotional liberation</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>22</highlightID>
      <text>
        In the course of developing emotional responsibility, most of us experience three stages: (1) "emotional slavery" - believing ourselves responsible for the feelings of others, (2) "the obnoxious stage" - in which we refuse to admit to caring what anyone else feels or needs, and (3) "emotional liberation"-in which we accept full responsibility for our own feelings but not the feelings of others, while being aware that we can never meet our own needs at the expense of others.
      </text>
      <location>61</location>
      <note>emotional slavery to emotional liberation</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>23</highlightID>
      <text>
        In addition to using positive language, we also want to word our requests in the form of concrete actions that others can undertake and to avoid vague, abstract, or ambiguous phrasing.
      </text>
      <location>69</location>
      <note>how to make requests</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>24</highlightID>
      <text>
        Like this father, we often use vague and abstract language to indicate how we want other people to feel or be without naming a concrete action they could take to reach that state.
      </text>
      <location>70</location>
      <note>how to not make requests</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>25</highlightID>
      <text>
        When we simply express our teelings, it may not be clear to the listener what we want them to do.
        We are often not conscious of what we are requesting.
        Requests may sound like demands when unaccompanied by the speaker's feelings and needs.
        The clearer we are about what we want, the more likely it is that we'll get it. 
      </text>
      <location>72,73,74</location>
      <note>how to make requests</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>26</highlightID>
      <text>
        If I clearly understand 
        you intend no demand, 
        I'll usually respond when you call. 
        But if you come across 
        like a high and mighty boss, 
        you'll feel like you ran into a wall. 
        And when you remind me 
        so piously 
        about all those things you've done for me, 
        you'd better get ready: 
        Here comes another bout! 
        Then you can shout, 
        you can spit, 
        moan, groan, and throw a fit; 
        I still won't take the garbage out. 
        Now even if you should change your style, 
        It's going to take me a little while 
        before I can forgive and forget. 
        Because it seems to me that you
        didn't see me as human too
        until all your standards were met.

        —"Song from Brett" by Marshall B. Rosenberg 
      </text>
      <location>84</location>
      <note>poem, Marshall Rosenberg poem</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>27</highlightID>
      <text>
        The Chinese philosopher Chuang-Tzu stated that true empathy requires listening with the whole being: "The hearing that is only in the ears is one thing. The hearing of the understanding is another. But the hearing of the spirit is not limited to any one faculty, to the ear, or to the mind. Hence it demands the emptiness of all the faculties. And when the faculties are empty, then the whole being listens.There is then a direct grasp of what is right there before you that can never be heard with the ear or understood with the mind."
      </text>
      <location>91</location>
      <note>eq, what is empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>28</highlightID>
      <text>
         Instead of offering empathy, we tend instead to give advice or reassurance and to explain our own position or feeling. Empathy, on the other hand, requires us to focus full attention on the other person's message. We give to others the time and space they need to express themselves fully and to feel understood.
      </text>
      <location>92</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>29</highlightID>
      <text>
         My friend Holley Humphrey identified some common behaviors that prevent us from being sufficiently present to connect empathi-cally with others. The following are examples: 
        •Advising: "I think you should … " "How come you didn't … ?" 
        •One-upping: "That's nothing; wait'll you hear what happened to me." 
        •Educating: "This could turn into a very positive experience for you if you just … " 
        •Consoling: "It wasn't your fault; you did the best you could." 
        •Story-telling: "That reminds me of the time … " 
        •Shutting down: "Cheer up. Don't feel so bad." 
        •Sympathizing: "Oh, you poor thing … " 
        •Interrogating: "When did this begin?" 
        •Explaining: "I would have called but … " 
        •Correcting: "That's not how it happened." 
      </text>
      <location>92,93</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>29</highlightID>
      <text>
         My friend Holley Humphrey identified some common behaviors that prevent us from being sufficiently present to connect empathi-cally with others. The following are examples: 
        •Advising: "I think you should … " "How come you didn't … ?" 
        •One-upping: "That's nothing; wait'll you hear what happened to me." 
        •Educating: "This could turn into a very positive experience for you if you just … " 
        •Consoling: "It wasn't your fault; you did the best you could." 
        •Story-telling: "That reminds me of the time … " 
        •Shutting down: "Cheer up. Don't feel so bad." 
        •Sympathizing: "Oh, you poor thing … " 
        •Interrogating: "When did this begin?" 
        •Explaining: "I would have called but … " 
        •Correcting: "That's not how it happened." 
      </text>
      <location>92,93</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>29</highlightID>
      <text>
         My friend Holley Humphrey identified some common behaviors that prevent us from being sufficiently present to connect empathi-cally with others. The following are examples: 
        •Advising: "I think you should … " "How come you didn't … ?" 
        •One-upping: "That's nothing; wait'll you hear what happened to me." 
        •Educating: "This could turn into a very positive experience for you if you just … " 
        •Consoling: "It wasn't your fault; you did the best you could." 
        •Story-telling: "That reminds me of the time … " 
        •Shutting down: "Cheer up. Don't feel so bad." 
        •Sympathizing: "Oh, you poor thing … " 
        •Interrogating: "When did this begin?" 
        •Explaining: "I would have called but … " 
        •Correcting: "That's not how it happened." 
      </text>
      <location>92,93</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>30</highlightID>
      <text>
         In fact, such intellectual understanding of a problem blocks the kind of presence that empathy requires. When we are thinking about people's words and listening to how they connect to our theories, we are looking at people - we are not with them. The key ingredient of empathy is presence: we are wholly present with the other party and what they are experiencing.
      </text>
      <location>93,94</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>31</highlightID>
      <text>
         The more we practice in this way, the more we realize a simple truth: behind all those messages we've allowed ourselves to be intimidated by are just individuals with unmet needs appealing to us to contribute to their well-being.
      </text>
      <location>99</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>32</highlightID>
      <text>
        As author and mythologist Joseph Campbell suggested, “‘What will they think of me?’ must be put aside for bliss.” We begin to feel this bliss when messages previously experienced as critical or blaming begin to be seen for the gifts they are: opportunities to give to people who are in pain.
      </text>
      <location>100</location>
      <note>empathy, eq, Joseph Campbell</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>33</highlightID>
      <text>
        We know a speaker has received adequate empathy when (1) we sense a release of tension, or (2) the flow of words comes to a halt.
      </text>
      <location>102</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>34</highlightID>
      <text>
        We need empathy to give empathy. When we sense ourselves being defensive or unable to empathize, we need to (1) stop, breathe, give ourselves empathy; (2) scream nonviolently; or (3) take time out.
      </text>
      <location>104</location>
      <note>empathy</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>36</highlightID>
      <text>
        Empathizing with someone’s “no” protects us from taking it personally.
      </text>
      <location>121</location>
      <note>empathy, no</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>37</highlightID>
      <text>
        What bores the listener bores the speaker too.
      </text>
      <location>123</location>
      <note>empathy, communication, secrets of adulthood?</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>38</highlightID>
      <text>
        In the play A Thousand Clowns by Herb Gardner, the protagonist refuses to release his twelve-year-old nephew to child-welfare authorities, declaring, “I want him to get to know exactly the special thing he is or else he won’t notice it when it starts to go. I want him to stay awake … I want to be sure he sees all the wild possibilities. I want him to know it’s worth  all the trouble just to give the world a little goosing when you get the chance. And I want him to know the subtle, sneaky, important reason why he was born a human being and not a chair.”
      </text>
      <location>129</location>
      <note>self compassion, eq, Herb Gardener</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>39</highlightID>
      <text>
        Avoid shoulding yourself!
      </text>
      <location>131</location>
      <note>my rules, self-compassion</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>40</highlightID>
      <text>
        NVC mourning: connecting with the feelings and unmet needs stimulated by past actions we now regret.
      </text>
      <location>133</location>
      <note>NVC mourning, self-compassion</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>41</highlightID>
      <text>
        NVC self-forgiveness: connecting with the need we were trying to meet when we took the action that we now regret.
      </text>
      <location>133</location>
      <note>self-forgiveness, self-compassion</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>42</highlightID>
      <text>
        When I advise, “Don’t do anything that isn’t play!” some take me to be radical, even insane.
      </text>
      <location>135</location>
      <note>play</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>43</highlightID>
      <text>
        Step 1: List on a piece of paper all those things that you tell yourself you have to do. List any activity you dread but do anyway because you perceive yourself to have no choice.

        Step2: List on a piece of paper all those things that you tell yourself you have to do. List any activity you dread but do anyway because you perceive yourself to have no choice.

        Step 3:After having acknowledged that you choose to do a particular activity, get in touch with the intention behind your choice by completing the statement, I choose to … because I want ….
      </text>
      <location>136,137</location>
      <note>how to translate Have to to Choose to </note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>44</highlightID>
      <text>
         I am convinced that after we gain clarity regarding the need being served by our actions, we can experience those actions as play even when they involve hard work, challenge, or frustration.
      </text>
      <location>138</location>
      <note>how to translate Have to to Choose to, play</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>45</highlightID>
      <text>
         When we make mistakes, instead of getting caught up in moralistic self-judgments, we can use the process of NVC mourning and self-forgiveness to show us where we can grow. By assessing our behaviors in terms of our own unmet needs, the impetus for change comes not out of shame, guilt, anger, or depression, but out of the genuine desire to contribute to our own and others’ well-being.
      </text>
      <location>140</location>
      <note>nvc self-knowledge</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>46</highlightID>
      <text>
         We are never angry because of what someone else did. We can identify the other person’s behavior as the stimulus, but it is important to establish a clear separation between stimulus and cause.
      </text>
      <location>142</location>
      <note>anger</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>47</highlightID>
      <text>
         The cause of anger lies in our thinking—in thoughts of blame and judgment.
      </text>
      <location>143</location>
      <note>anger</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>48</highlightID>
      <text>
         This may take extensive practice, whereby over and over again, we consciously replace the phrase “I am angry because they … “ with “I am angry because I am needing … “ 
      </text>
      <location>144</location>
      <note>anger, how to deal with anger</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>49</highlightID>
      <text>
         When we become aware of our needs, anger gives way to life-serving feelings.
      </text>
      <location>146</location>
      <note>anger</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>50</highlightID>
      <text>
         All violence is the result of people tricking themselves, as did this young man, into believing that their pain derives from other people and that consequently those people deserve to be punished. 
      </text>
      <location>147</location>
      <note>anger, violence</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>51</highlightID>
      <text>
         Steps to expressing anger: 
          1. Stop. Breathe. 
          2. Identify our judgmental thoughts. 
          3. Connect with our needs. 
          4. Express our feelings and unmet needs.
      </text>
      <location>149</location>
      <note>expressing anger</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>52</highlightID>
      <text>
         Stay conscious of the violent thoughts that arise in our minds, without judging them.
      </text>
      <location>150</location>
      <note>expressing anger, mindfulness</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>53</highlightID>
      <text>
         I had a major conflict with what went on in his head, but I’ve learned that I enjoy human beings more if I don’t hear what they think. Especially with folks who have his kind of thoughts. I’ve learned to savor life much more by only hearing what’s going on in their hearts and not getting caught up with the stuff in their heads. 
      </text>
      <location>151</location>
      <note>expressing anger, hreart not thought</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>54</highlightID>
      <text>
        Practice translating each judgment into an unmet need.
      </text>
      <location>153</location>
      <note>judgement into unmet need</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>55</highlightID>
      <text>
        The intention behind the protective use of force is to prevent injury or injustice. The intention behind the punitive use of force is to cause individuals to suffer for their perceived misdeeds.
      </text>
      <location>161</location>
      <note>use of force</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>56</highlightID>
      <text>
        Punishment also includes judgmental labeling and the withholding of privileges.
      </text>
      <location>163</location>
      <note>punishing</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>57</highlightID>
      <text>
        Question 1: What do I want this person to do? 
        Question 2: What do I want this person’s reasons to be for doing it? 
      </text>
      <location>165</location>
      <note>limitations of punishment</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>58</highlightID>
      <text>
        Notice how these inner messages are infested with judgmental terms and phrases such as should, wasting my education and talents, and can’t handle. Variations of this dialogue had been running in his woman’s head for months. She was asked to imagine the “career woman” voice taking an “NVC pill” in order to restate its message in the following form: “When a, I feel b, because I am needing c. Therefore I now would like d.” 
      </text>
      <location>173</location>
      <note>how to resolve internal conflict</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>59</highlightID>
      <text>
        Focus on what we want to do rather than what went wrong.
      </text>
      <location>174</location>
      <note>what to do</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>60</highlightID>
      <text>
        Defuse stress by empathizing with others.
      </text>
      <location>175</location>
      <note>stress</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>61</highlightID>
      <text>
        … the more you become a connoisseur of gratitude, the less you are a victim of resentment, depression, and despair. Gratitude will act as an elixir that will gradually dissolve the hard shell of your ego - your need to possess and control - and transform you into a generous being. The sense of gratitude produces true spiritual alchemy, makes us magnanimous - large souled.
          - Sam Keen, philosopher
      </text>
      <location>184</location>
      <note>eq, Sam Keen</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>62</highlightID>
      <text>
        Compliments are often judgments—however positive-of others.
      </text>
      <location>185</location>
      <note>compliments</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>63</highlightID>
      <text>
        Express appreciation to celebrate, not to manipulate.
      </text>
      <location>186</location>
      <note>compliments</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>64</highlightID>
      <text>
        NVC encourages us to receive appreciation with the same quality of empathy we express when listening to other messages. We hear what we have done that has contributed to others’ well-being; we hear their feelings and the needs that were fulfilled. We take into our hearts the joyous reality that we can each enhance the quality of others’ lives.
      </text>
      <location>188</location>
      <note>receiving compliments</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>65</highlightID>
      <text>
        Receive appreciation without feelings of superiority or false humility.
      </text>
      <location>189</location>
      <note>receiving compliments</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>66</highlightID>
      <text>
        The following lines, attributed to contemporary writer Marianne Williamson, serve as another reminder for me to avoid the pitfall of false humility:

        Our deepest fear is not that we are inadequate. Our deepest fear is that we are powerful beyond measure. 
        It is our light, not our darkness, that frightens us. You are a child of God. Your playing small doesn’t serve the world. 
        There’s nothing enlightened about shrinking so that other people won’t feel insecure around you. 
        We were born to make manifest the glory of God that is within us. It’s not just in some of us, it is in everyone. 
        And as we let our own light shine, we unconsciously give other people permission to do the same. 
        As we are liberated from our fear, our presence automatically liberates others.       
      </text>
      <location>189</location>
      <note>eq, Marianne Williamson, compliments</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>67</highlightID>
      <text>
        That evening I wrote a song that began like this: 
        If I’m ninety-eight percent perfect in anything I do, 
        it’s the two percent I’ve messed up 
        I’ll remember when I’m through. </text>
      <location>191</location>
      <note>compliments</note>
    </highlight>

    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <highlightID>9</highlightID>
      <reference>Less Than One</reference>
      <referenceauthors>Joseph Bodsky</referenceauthors>
      <toRead>1</toRead>
      <location>xxv</location>
      <note>Book to read. Essays </note>
    </highlight>


  </highlights>
</book>

