<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" type="text/xml" href="style.xsl"?><!--
    The "isNoteOnly" attribute on the highlight element indicates that the child
    text element contains automatically selected context around a user's note, but
    was not text explicitly highlighted by the user.
-->
<book>
  <title>Thomas Jefferson: Lessons from a Secret Buddha</title>
  <authors>Suneel Dhand</authors>
  <highlights>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>The Second Ancient Principle is just this very belief. To always keep a great thirst for knowledge. The ability to learn is our greatest talent.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=283">283</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Keep in mind, too, that the quest for knowledge and being a learned person is also about absorbing everything else around you.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=301">301</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>“I cannot live without books. . . . Knowledge indeed is a desirable, a lovely possession.”</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=324">324</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Mastering the art of discipline will enable you to be successful in everything you do.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=371">371</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>One of the most important rules we keep is to always awake early every morning. We believe in the magical power of the mornings and never slumber into a late awakening, as there is undoubtedly something about the early rays</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=375">375</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>of sunlight that helps to inspire. Upon awakening, we set aside time to think carefully about all that we would like to accomplish on that day, visualizing the morning, afternoon, and evening. Typically, we put pen to paper and write down our plans, for we believe that a plan not committed to paper is no plan at all. We seek to be as productive as we can early in the day, the best time to get work done. I have already told you about our eating, exercise, and reading habits, which help</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=376">376</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Each day we are also sure to set aside time for relaxing, pleasurable activities, and spending quality</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=383">383</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>time with our families. A healthy balance is always needed.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=384">384</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>“Whether I retire to bed early or late, I rise with the sun.”</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=409">409</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>“I never go to bed without an hour, or half hour’s previous reading of something moral, whereon to ruminate in the intervals of sleep.”</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=437">437</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>mind always employed is</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=443">443</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>always happy.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=444">444</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>This is to always endeavor to maintain a calm mind, even in the most worrisome of situations. A spirit of calmness is needed in all of our pursuits if one is to truly succeed. There</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=536">536</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>“Never think of taking a book with you. The object of walking</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=580">580</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>to relax the mind. You should therefore not permit yourself even to think while you walk. But divert your attention by the objects surrounding you.”</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=581">581</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>“Nothing gives one person so much advantage over another as to remain always cool and unruffled under all circumstances. . . . When angry, count ten before you speak; if very angry, a hundred. . . . Take things always by their smooth handle.”</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=587">587</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>A man’s home is his castle, and we believe that you can tell much about a person from their</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=615">615</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Our people have been doing this for centuries, because being totally self-sufficient and not dependent on others is most crucial for any society.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=659">659</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Value good character above all else and practice only the best human virtues. Be honest, sincere, kind, compassionate, and gentle. Be forgiving and show empathy.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=716">716</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>To walk safely through the maze of human life, one needs the light of wisdom and the guidance of virtue. Just</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=719">719</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>In a controversy, the instant we feel anger, we have already ceased striving for the truth, and have begun striving for ourselves.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=732">732</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>We are shaped by our thoughts, we become what we think, and with our thoughts, we make the world.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=737">737</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>The thought manifests as the word. The word manifests as the deed. The deed develops into habit. And the habit hardens into character.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=739">739</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>The Sixth Ancient Principle is to live a life of purpose. Indeed, a life without one is somewhat meaningless. We need a reason to get up every morning, something we really believe in. It is a travesty to just go through the motions.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=878">878</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Whatever you are doing in life, belief in success or failure is often a self-fulfilling prophecy.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=993">993</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>Focus on the present moment always, and all the opportunities you have right here and now.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=1053">1053</location>
    </highlight>
    <highlight isNoteOnly="false">
      <text>The best things in our lives that produce happiness are simultaneously free and priceless.</text>
      <location url="kindle://book?action=open&amp;asin=B008E3GWQG&amp;location=1054">1054</location>
    </highlight>
  </highlights>
</book>